[Music]
so this is what I wrote on Facebook
which got me more attention and comments
and discussion than anything I've ever
practically written before this is what
I wrote if your only image of a man is a
domineering male oppressor and this is
what you get
monster demigods like Harvey Weinstein
and Donald Trump I suggest that we at
the very least need to cultivate a more
positive view of men and perhaps more
noble gentle men will arise we need to
remember that despite the glass ceiling
for women men have been traditionally
disposable and more time they die about
six years younger on average they do
most of the dangerous jobs they keep the
infrastructure running they're more
susceptible to drugs and alcohol and
violent crime and suicide suicide among
young men is astronomical and of course
it's mostly men who are filling up our
prisons and learn thick asylums
so even though a man have a lot of power
and often use their power and negative
ways towards women at the same time men
kind of suffer in in ways that is not
always acknowledged I feel and and
because often men don't have the courage
to talk about it or else they talk about
it in this cheesy kind of aggressive way
so anyway is there anything to love
about men since men do all the bad
things in the world apparently surely
there is a place for men you know and
for men's vitality and even virility
ensure that our job is not merely to
tame and chastise and socialize and I
would say all that means castrate men
mmm I think the first couple ways of
feminism and I've been very good for men
and women generally and helped us to
understand as I said before that men are
the same and that men are different
maybe the third and fourth wave of
feminism has been problematic in some
ways so maybe we need a fifth wave of
feminism so I'd say there's a pretty
negative view of men these days and in
the media and for probably good reason
at the same time I think gender bashing
is unappropriate and has to go you know
on all fronts
our image of men's to be balanced and
I'm not talking about some kind of
cheesy conservative men's movement or
for their polarization but I am talking
about cherishing loving men more and I'm
would like to suggest that real men are
not interested in mere powered
domination mere fucking I'd say real men
don't give a shit about power unless
it's when I say real men I mean a real
manliness is about not giving a shit
about of power actually it's about being
noble self-sacrificing and it's only
about power in the senses about the
power of maybe creativity and
transformation intelligence of course
what that the same thing goes for women
as well
but nobody's saying that when it comes
to men
so all these men who get caught with
their dick in their hand engaged in
disgusting acts why are they so
powerless surely they need to be
empowered when it comes to their
relationship to nubile young women for
instance and why are women so powerless
in front of real or imagined power it
seems like so many men seem to be at
this level of arrested emotional sexual
development and apparently they're
incapable of saying yes or no and these
are the same people with immense worldly
power so with the Nick Euler codes and
and whatnot which is rather scary and it
seems to me that there are many people
in high places that are not really men
or not really women they're more like
girls and boys and that's also scary so
what should we do about all this I think
the remedy is to become a complete
person and what does that mean that
means meeting the other could be the
other sex or the other just the other
person and as deep away as possible
I'm not isolating oneself
we should meet the other in all her his
glorious other nests that's how we
destroy the immature person note I don't
exclude any other kind of relationship
here relationship is always about
polarity no matter what kind of bodies
you're talking about there's what's the
Taoists call a flowery war I really like
that expression between men and women
between the two polarities well that's
pretty obvious these days but such a war
should be not nasty and underhanded but
more like a dance not something
beautiful which requires humility rather
than gender bashing so I hear a lot of
people talk about how we're moving from
this patriarchal age into a matriarchal
age that gets people pretty excited but
that's still polarity that's still about
dominating others so men have dominated
others for thousands of years apparently
you know women would like to dominate
men or would they if you're only talking
about power
and if women suddenly ruled the world
then we would still be in a dynamic of
domination it would be the same game
just upside down so I'd like to suggest
that ruling is not about power but it's
about complementarity and
complementarity as is that the root of
all positive transformation it exists
when we consider the other bow rather
than it to refer to Martin Buber the it
is the object okay we are not objects we
are sacred to each other so I would say
that we need to actually worship each
other again
to restore the positive archetype of the
noble heroic man along with the noble
and heroic woman so that we can both
rule and this is the I would say that
primarily religious impulse it's the
symbol behind
spiritual truth it's the union of the
the male and the and the female the
masculine and the feminine we tend to
think that evolution is about progress
our Ahmet emancipation from these
tyrannical demigods or men of power but
the next question is you know what will
we do when we're free of all these
tyrannical men when we've rid the world
of psychopathic men of power what comes
next
we love stories of emancipation and the
downfall of the tyrant but we're much
less attracted to stories about the
morning after but that's when the real
work begins the problem is that
emancipation is only half the story the
second half is less dramatic the second
half is about responsibility and
complementarity I would argue not just
rights
Nietzsche may have been wrong when he
said we've killed God maybe we've just
anesthetized him
maybe the patriarch Jehovah doesn't
really die he just goes underground if
he is repressed that is it's not a good
thing to repress the patriarch or the
matriarch if you repress the patriarch
you get a lot of powerless and
unconscious men in power that's what's
happening the tyrannical unconscious men
of power have whole armies at their
beckoning and yet they appear to be so
out of touch with their bodies and minds
to put it mildly and that is not a good
thing to understate the case again so
it's not really my place to make this
kind of declaration but I hope somebody
will soon I propose that fist the fifth
wave of feminism should be characterized
by women adoring men again and also men
adoring women of course other forms of
adoration should be welcomed as well
that goes without saying in my book
the fact is that most men benefit most
from adoring women and women benefit by
adoring men that's how the polarities of
the universe are dying to to meet and
come together in and clash and that's
how the child of creativity is born if
there is no adoration then people remain
angry and bitter and polarized they
remain impotent half people
revolutionaries or bloodthirsty I would
just like to smash the the system but
don't really have anything to to offer
after they've destroyed the the
patriarchy
so when the tyrant is finally overthrown
who and and what and how will we put the
highest in that place whatever that
happens to be what just probably beyond
male and female in some sense it's just
the principle of the highest and that
needs to be reinstated otherwise you
have a flat world where everybody is
just one gender and that's a natural and
it doesn't work at least that's what I
think anyway so thank you for listening